Chebesi Awah

Communauté urbaine de Douala, Littoral, Cameroon

chebesiawah@gmail.com

+237677972126

linkedin.com/in/chebesi-awah-b891331ab

Summary

I am a solution-oriented and problem solver with over three years of experience building and maintaining software and software architecture. Highly skilled in communication, collaboration, and technical documentation, and am very enthusiastic about creating high-performing web and mobile applications using the best technologies. The tech sector is vast and ever changing which requires constant learning and relearning. This is what is most exciting about Software Development I am interested in music, Politics, agriculture, soccer, and I look forward to connecting with you!

Experience

Frontend Web and Mobile Developer

MDRN

May 2023 - Dec 2023 (8 months)

My role was to transform designs like Figma, PSD, etc into pixel perfect,responsive websites and mobile applications that are highly scalable.

I also wrote down the documentation of the projects I worked on, and did the maintainance on some existing Mobile Applications.

Frontend Web Developer

EVOLOAD

Jan 2023 - Feb 2023 (2 months)

As a Frontend Developer ,my role was to work with React to create the User Interface ,making sure that the User Experienced is top notch, and applying React best practices to make my code clean and readable for future developers who might need to work on my code for maintenance. Using CSS3 and other CSS frameworks like Material UI to style the web pages and give it a smooth and beautiful Look.

Frontend Developer

wereReallyGood.com

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022 (3 months)

Coming in as the Frontend developer and having to work remotely was exciting. But Using React and Redux of which I have a leveraged experience was more fun.

I had to contribute ideas on the nature of the product and best JavaScript Framework to use, Research and decide which platform to host on

Code the entire project

Manage and maintain existing projects

Learn New technologies to be able to contribute to the backend

🎁 Freelance Web Developer

Icemix Networks

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022 (10 months)

I had to contribute ideas on the nature of the product and best JavaScript Framework to use,

- Research and decide which platform to host on
- Code the entire project
- Manage and maintain existing projects
- Learn New technologies to be able to contribute to the backend

Frontend Web Developer

Virtual Pro Gaming

Sep 2021 - Nov 2021 (3 months)

I worked on a project that used React Js and Typescript. Using React Query, I had to interact with the server, getting data from the back and displaying it on the client side. I also updated the User Interface of the client side using libraries like Materia UI.

Frontend Developer

Debima LLC

Jan 2020 - Sep 2021 (1 year 9 months)

Develope a component system for our internal applications.

Translate UI designs into code and good UX using Tailwindcss, Reactjs

Intergrate our APIs

Work with other developers to map out plans for new projects and features, develop wireframes and Q/ A new ideas.

Maintain the companies marketing websites and technical documentation.

Contribute to backend development whenever necessary.

Full-stack Developer

BEWOCA NGO

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 (3 months)

As a Frontend Developer ,my role was to work with React to create the User Interface ,making sure that the User Experienced is top notch, and applying React best practices to make my code clean and readable for future developers who might need to work on my code for maintenance. Using CSS3 and other CSS frameworks like Material UI to style the web pages and give it a smooth and beautiful Look.

Education

University of Yaounde' 2 Soa

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Law and Public Administration Oct 2011 - Aug 2014

Licenses & Certifications



JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures - freeCodeCamp

fccd9ff51ad-ee2b-49ac-bdb2-422d3b15a5c2

Skills

React Native • Expo • TypeScript • Vue.js • React.js • JavaScript • Node Js • React • CSS • HTMI